Welcome, this is a tutorial on
how to use Gl치nGuide.
Gl치nGuide is an accessibility checker in
which you can enter a URL
of any specific website or web
page and it will grade on
how accessible this web page is
on a variety of parameters.
To start off, will take this
URL here to the Tea Dublin
homepage. I'm inserting it into
the top input field.
And pressing 'Check'. This
is now printing out the code
to this web page, which you
can minimise by pressing the 'Collapse
Code' button and maximising by pressing
'Expand Code'. I can
filter this code into
images, anchors, alt text, links,
buttons, input fields. To do
so, I click on one such filter such
as images and then press the 'Filter'
button.
The accessibility grade. A
can be filtered as well. It can
grade per the filter. Or
across the whole web page. Each
error and warning is listed below.
Errors are in red, warnings are
in orange. Down below
on the web page are multiple
educational articles on the different
aspects of accessibility. Here in the
How to use Gl치nGuide is
a text based, along with, images
how-to tutorial on the use
of Gl치nGuide. Thank you and
I hope this video was informative.